[AUDIO LOGO]
INSTRUCTOR: Hey, everyone.
I hope you are doing well.
Purpose of this
video is to show you
how to use the new Azure Visual
Desktop to load SQL Server
Management Studio.
SQL Server Management
Studio is the software
that we use in both
DATA 3330 and DATA 4330
to connect to the server,
and we will either
be using the darksaber.usu.edu
server or stairway.usu.edu.
So if you're new, SQL
Server Management Studio
is like a web browser
in the sense that
to connect to, for
instance, Amazon,
you need that web
browser to connect
to the database at Amazon.
And so we use SQL Server
Management Studio.
That's not the database,
but that's the mechanism
that we use to connect to
either Darksaber or to Stairway.
You can also use Beekeeper which
is described in the syllabus
as well.
I first want to point out
that SQL Server Management
Studio is available in all
Huntsman Computer Labs.
This is the only one we
have complete control over.
And Tom James, our lab manager
for the Huntsman School,
does a great job of keeping
it fully operational.
To use the Visual Desktop, I'm
going to use or demonstrate
this on a Mac.
And so there's a couple
of things that you need.
And first, regardless of how
you connect to the server,
you'll need to be
logged into the USU VPN.
And we have the link
in the syllabus.
And as a reminder, if I click
at the top of the screen,
you can see the bottom
part of the GlobalProtect.
Every once in a
while, you do have
to click the three
little dashes at the top
and have it reset
so you can log in.
But right now, you
can see that we are
connected to the GlobalProtect.
So that's step number one.
The second step would be
to download on your Mac,
if you don't have it yet.
The Windows app at
the Microsoft Store.
So you download the Windows
app at the Microsoft Store.
And once you have
that downloaded,
I can click on the
Windows app on my Mac.
And so in this case, it
didn't ask me for the login.
So if I were to log in, I
do need to click on the plus
and I would click on Add
Work or School Account.
When I do that it brings
up the Windows app.
And for here you'll
type in your A number.
And then @aggies.usu.edu.
And you'll click Next, and
then use your password.
And when you type
that in, assuming
that you're logged
into the GlobalProtect,
you should get this screen here.
Joseph
Murray is our primary
contact for troubleshooting
with this app.
And if he can't help you,
he can forward the issue
onto Tom James.
SQL Server Management
Studio is on the screen.
And again, assuming that
you're connected to the VPN,
it will start the remote PC
and run SQL Server Management
Studio.
As you can see, in this case,
it's fairly slow to load.
Did I remind you can always use
the computer lab in the Huntsman
School, the Eccles Building?
And so this right now
does look much better
than what Citrix does.
The login information will
be provided both in Canvas
and in the syllabus,
but you will always
use the database engine.
And here you'll either select
stairway.usu.edu or Darksaber.
Darksaber.
Usu.edu.
We will use SQL Server
Authentication, not
your Windows Authentication.
Your login will be either 3330,
underscore, your first name
and last name, all lowercase and
your password will be database.
And then you will
connect to the server.
Again, if you have any
questions or problems,
don't spend a whole
afternoon trying to log in.
If you add the
course late, there
is a chance that we haven't
added you to the database yet.
And it's rare because
Joseph, Claire and the team,
they do an incredible job of
adding you to the database,
but there's sometimes
a misspelling.
We use the first and last name
as we see it in Canvas too.
This represents an overview.
Again, you'll have the
global connect on a Mac.
You'll have the Windows app.
You'll log into the Windows app.
You'll see on the syllabus
through your A number
@aggies.usu.edu and
your hard password.
And then when I was
logging in here,
it did take a couple of minutes
and it took me two tries
to get in.
Hopefully, as I continue to log
in the connection, some of that
will be loaded or preloaded
and be more efficient.
So that is the login process
for the Azure database,
using, in this case, a Mac.
Let me close this
down for a moment.
So we just covered the login
to SQL Server Management Studio
using Azure Virtual Desktop.
You can also download SQL
Server Management Studio Express
onto your PC.
I think we also have a website
that you can use to log in.
Windows.cloud.microsoft.
And then as a
reminder, you can also
use other programs,
Beekeeper, or if you
have a different program that
you use for an internship
or something, you're more than
welcome to use that as well.
So I hope that's helpful and
we will talk to you soon.
Take care.